Charles Lee Remington Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Newspaper Clippings, Series IV
  - Cockroaches. News paper clippings on Charles Lee Remingtons work with cockroaches., 001745
  - Miscellaneous. Miscellaneous newspaper clippings featuring Charles Lee Remington. Topics range from fireflies to coyotes., 001748
  - Program Announcments. Newspaper clippings of Charles Lee Remingtons events, lectures, or programs in which he offered or was featured., 001747
  - Yale News. Charles Lee Remingtons appearances in Yale affiliated journels, Yale radio stations and Yale television reports., 001744
- Biographical Materials, Series V
  Charles Lee Remingtons Biographical Material including personal & family history.
  - Biographical Information. EST number of items = 50+., 001416
  - C V's. EST number of items = 10+., 001417
  - Contacts. Personal and professional contacts., 001418
  - Family History. EST number of items = 50., 001413
  - Harvard University. Charles Lee Remmington' Archives from the time he spent at Harvard University where He recived his PhD in 1948. Includes course work, grades and miscellaneous archives. EST number of items = 40+., 1946-1948; 001449
  - Obituaries. Collection of Charles Lee Remington's obituaries and death notices. EST number of items = 30+., 2007; 001415
  - Personal Identification. Birth certificates, social security card, drivers permit etc. EST number of items = 10+., 001414
  - Principia. Archives including coursework, bird & insect information and other miscellaneous papers from when Charles Lee Remmington attended Principia Collage., 1939-1942; 001450
  - WWII. Charles Lee Remingtons archives from WWII including G.I. information, Japan information, and wartime data. EST number of items = 100+., 1943-1949; 001447
- Parks & Land Trust Information, Series VI
  Archives related to Parks & Land Trust's that Charles Lee Remington was involved in. Contains park information, programs, permits etc.
  - East Rock. EST number of items = 30+., 1988-1989; 001408
  - Long Wharf Preserve. EST number of items = 100., 1992-1998; 001409
  - New Haven Land Trust. New Haven Land Trust comitee papers, programs, and land ecology. EST number of items = 50+., 1965-1997; 001410
  - New York City Parks. EST number of items = 10+., 1985-1986; 001411
  - Quinipiac Watershed Project. EST number of objects = 15+., 1996-1997; 001821
  - West River Memorial Park. West River Memorial Park insect surveys, memorandums, and published work. EST number of items = 70., 001720
  - West Rock. West Rock ecology, programs, newsletters and association information. EST number of items = 70., 1974-2009; 001407
  - Yale Natural Preserve. Number of items = 2., 1965; 001412
- Zero Population Growth, 1968-1998; Series VII
  - Board. Miscellaneaous ZPG board archives including meeting notes., 001458
  - Congress on Optimum Population & Environment. Miscellaneuous archives from Charles Lee Remington relating to the 1st & 2nd National Congress on Optimum Population & Environment. EST number of items = 100+., 1969-1972; 001455
  - Connecticut. Miscellaneaous ZPG b archives relating to all CT chapters., 001459
  - Funds. Fund information, including ZPG fund & Equilibrium fund. EST number of items = 100+., 1973-1975; 001454
  - Growth Alternitives & Goals. Miscellaneuous archives from Charles Lee Remington relating to the ZPG growth alternitives and goals. EST number of items = 50+., 1969-1974; 001456
  - Newsletters. Newsletters and annual reports related to Zero Population Growth., 1970-1975; 001453
  - Publications &Newspaper Clippings. Miscellaneous publications & newspaper clippings and coppies of articles realting to Zero Population Growth. EST number of items = 25+., 1969-1979; 001452
  - Speeches. Speeches given by Charles Lee Remington relating to ZPG. Number of items = 3., 001457
- Day Planners, 1969-2001; Series VIII
  Day planners kept by Charles Lee Remington. Number of items = 33.
  - 1969-1971., 001461
  - 1972-1974., 001462
  - 1976-1978. No planner for 1975., 001463
  - 1979-1981., 001464
  - 1982-1984., 001465
  - 1985-1987., 001466
  - 1988-1990., 001467
  - 1991-1993., 001468
  - 1994-1996., 001469
  - 1997-1999., 001470
  - 2000-2001., 001471
- Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory, Series IX
  Charles Lee Remmington owned land on the Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory where he vacationed and did research.
  - Brochures. EST number of items = 10., 001476
  - Member Lists., 1955-1994; 001474
  - NFS Grants. NFS grant information & land acquisition notes pertaning to the Rocky Mountain Biological laboratory. EST number of items = 5., 1957-1964; 001475
  - Remington Cabin. EST number of items = 10-., 001473
- Affiliated Projects, Series X
  Miscellaneous projects Charles Lee Remington was affiliated with.
  - Beinecke Freezer. EST number of items = 25+., 1977-1984; 001482
  - Bethany Bog. EST number of items = 25+., 1973-1997; 001478
  - Cicadas. Archives relating to Charles Lee Remmingtons Cicada project. Includes data, newspaper clips, notes, and photographs. EST number of items = 50+., 1993-1998; 001483
  - Eating Insects. EST number of items = 50+., 001479
  - Gynandromorphs. EST number of items = 50+., 001481
  - Suture Zones. EST number of items = 50+., 001480
- Published Works, Series XI
  Charles Lee Remingtons published work including manuscripts, articles etc.
  - Encyclopedia Entries. Charles Lee Remingtons published entries into encyclopedias etc including; Websters, Britannica, Readers Digest, & the Encyclopedia of Paleontology., 1955-1979; 001492
  - John Abbot. Copy of publication and research materials Charles Lee Remington used for Brief Biographies, John Abbot., 001750
  - Order Thysanura & Order Entotrophi., 1954; 001488
  - Plates. Original plates and pictures used in published work., 002769
  - Reviews. Miscelaneous book, manuscript, and NSF reviews., 001493
  - Short Notes. Charles Lee Remingtons published short notes, mostly in Lepid. news., 1946-1955; 001491
  - The Apterygota., 1954; 001490
  - The Distribution of Hemiargus in Isola East of the Mississippi River., 1942; 001487
  - The Genetics of Colias., 1954; 001486
  - The Rhopalocera of Principia College., 1943; 001485
  - The Supra-Generic Classification of the order Thysanur (Insecta)., 1954; 001489
  - Thesis. Thysanura., 002692
- Unpublished Works, Series XII
  A collection of Charles Lee Remingtons unpublished work.
  - A Passion For Insects., 2001; 001495
  - Genetics of Speciation., 1977; 001500
  - Genetics of Variability in a Conspicously Polymorphic Moth., 001496
  - Mimicry., 001503
  - Molluscs. Carles Lee Remingtons unpublished manuscript on molluscs., 001759
  - Multiple Antennal Rami: an asymmetrical abnormality in a Cordulegaster maculatus nymph (Odonata). Burchenal, Joan R. & Charles L. Remington., [1992]; 000179
  - New Records of Lepidoptera., 1950; 001498
  - Review., 001504
  - The Adjustment of Meotic Timing to Environmetal Stress in Male Lepidoptra., 001502
  - The Chromosomes of 22 Species of Papilionoidea from Tropical Africa., 1960; 001499
  - Theclini in Connecticut., 1956; 001501
  - Wintering Moths., 1971-1979; 001497
- Data Sets, Series XIII
  - Ant Lions. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Ant Lions., 001860
  - Beak Mark. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington for Beak mark related data., 001510
  - Blattaria. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Blattaria Breeding., 001511
  - CT Sibling Species Pairs. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on CT sibling species pairs., 001517
  - Callosamia & Hyalophora. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Callosamia & Hyalophora breeding., 001514
  - Chromosomes Hesperiidae. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & K. Maeki on Chromosomes Hesperiidae., 1959-1960; 001524
  - Chromosomes Lycaenidae. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & K. Maeki on Chromosomes Lycaenidae., 1959; 001523
  - Chromosomes Miscellaneous. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & K. Maeki on miscellaneous Chromosomes., 001529
  - Chromosomes Nymphalidae. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & K. Maeki on Chromosomes Nymphalidae., 1959; 001526
  - Chromosomes Papilionidae. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & K. Maeki on Chromosomes Papilionidae., 1959; 001527
  - Chromosomes Pieridae. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & K. Maeki on Chromosomes Pieridae., 1959; 001528
  - Chromosomes Satyridae. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & K. Maeki on Chromosomes Satyridae., 1959; 001525
  - Cisseps Rearings. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & J.E Remington on Cisseps Rearings., 1956; 001519
  - Colias. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Colias including breeding, literature, lab & feild data., 001507
  - Gypsy Moths. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Gypsy Moths., 001758
  - Lepidoptera Testes. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Lepidoptera Testes., 001508
  - Lepidoptera. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Lepidoptera rearings & food plant choices., 001516
  - Limenitis. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Limenitis., 1958-1966; 001513
  - Mark-Release-Recapture. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington for marek-release-recapture., 001509
  - Oak Galls. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & Jeanne E. Remington on Oak Galls., 1946-1948; 001721
  - Papilio. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Papilio including breeding, hybrid, Fred Thorne rearings and miscellaneous data., 001506
  - Phyciodes Crosses. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & C.G. Oliver on Phyciodes crosses., 1975-1977; 001518
  - Rearing Data. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & R.W. Pease on Rearing. Notebook., 001521
  - Super 7 survey. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & V. Demasi., 1990; 001824
  - Thysanuran. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Thysanuran., 001515
  - Utetheisa. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington & R.W. Pease on Utethesia. Brood data., 001520
  - Zerene. Data sets for research done by Charles Lee Remington on Zerene., 001512
- Formal Documents, Series XIV
  Charles Lee Remingtons formal documants including, academic apointments, leave of absence requests and honors awarded.
  - Academic Appoitments. Charles Lee Remingtons formal academic appoitments from Yale University., 1949-1992; 001534
  - Leave of Absence. Miscellaneous leave of absence requests and approvals from Yale University for Charles Lee Remington., 001536
  - Salary Increases. Charles Lee Remingtons formal salary increases from Yale University., 1958-1982; 001386
- Field Notes, Series XV
  Charles Lee Remingtons field notes.
  - California Islands. Charles Lee Remingtons field notes from California Islands., 001718
  - Colorado. Charles Lee Remingtons field notes from Colorado 1949-1955., 001717
  - Connecticut. Charles Lee Remingtons field notes from Connecticut 1949-1962., 001716
  - Galapagos., 1979; 001760
  - Miscellaneous. Charles Lee Remingtons miscellaneous field notes., 001761
- California Island Literature, Series XVI
  - Flora. Flora Literature associated with Charles Lee Remmingtons California Island project., 002100
  - General. General Literature associated with Charles Lee Remmingtons California Island project., 002099
  - Invertebrates. Invertabrate Literature associated with Charles Lee Remmingtons California Island project., 002102
  - Other Islands. Other Island Literature associated with Charles Lee Remmingtons California Island project., 002105
  - Santa Cruz Island. Santa Cruz Island Literature associated with Charles Lee Remmingtons California Island project., 002103
  - Santa Rosa Island. Santa Rosa Island Literature associated with Charles Lee Remmingtons California Island project., 002104
  - Vertebrates. Vertabrate Literature associated with Charles Lee Remmingtons California Island project., 002101
- Awards & Honors, Series XVII
  - 35th Anniversary Honorary Reception. Archives from the celebration of Charles Lee Remington's 35th anniversary at Yale. Honors were awarded and a fund was set up in his name., 1983; 002712
  - 50th Anniversary Of The Lepidopterist Society. Archives from the celebration of the 50th anniversary of the lepidopterists society in wich a book was put together for Charles Lee Remington who was not able to attend., 1997; 002713
  - Diplomas. In Map folders., 002734
  - Honors. Miscellaneous awards and honors earned by Charles Lee Remington., 001537
  - Retirement. Archives from the celebration of Charles Lee Remington's retirement., 1992; 002711
- Multimedia, Series XVIII
  Photographs and slides.
  - Photographs., 002717